<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><extraction><clueid>118831293</clueid><fullpath><![CDATA[https://github.com/mapsforge/mapsforge/issues/177]]></fullpath><realpath><![CDATA[https://github.com/mapsforge/mapsforge/issues/177]]></realpath><theme>mapsforgex_item</theme><middle>default</middle><createdate>2015-8-23 17:52:46</createdate><baseURI><bucketBaseURI><bucketName>BR</bucketName><uri><![CDATA[https://github.com/mapsforge/mapsforge/issues/177]]></uri></bucketBaseURI></baseURI>
<BR><item><id>#177</id><title>MapView logic tied into MapActivity, making it impossible to work with Fragments</title><description>

    
      
          From idan...@gmail.com on September 24, 2011 16:03:32

Currently, the logic in MapView is integrated with MapActivity. That didn't use to be a problem until Fragment was introduced in Honeycomb.

This makes it impossible to use a maps fragment as part as an activity. You can in theory use a MapActivity, but this solution is not clean and may affect other fragments.

I've managed to workaround the issue by refactoring MapActivity and MapView, so that MapActivity actually implements a new interface named MapContext which MapView relies on instead.

Attached is the patch I'm currently using. I have also created MapFragment which is not part of the patch, and is being used here: https://market.android.com/details?id=org.idansof.otp.ui&amp;feature=search_result https://code.google.com/p/otp-android/

Attachment: mapsforge-mapcontext.patch

Original issue: http://code.google.com/p/mapsforge/issues/detail?id=177
      
    

  </description><comments><item><commenter>mapsforge</commenter><contents>

    
      
          From thilo.mu...@gmail.com on January 07, 2012 09:08:46

Issue 141 has been merged into this issue.
      
    

  </contents></item><item><commenter>mapsforge</commenter><contents>

    
      
          From vincent....@gmail.com on May 14, 2012 01:13:34

(Sorry for the double post)

Beware, this patch also include a bug fix in the MapView file (the overlayController thread was not stopped properly).
      
    

  </contents></item><item><commenter>mapsforge</commenter><contents>

    
      
          From LudwigBr...@gmail.com on December 19, 2012 00:27:19

Issue 384 has been merged into this issue.
      
    

  </contents></item><item><commenter>mapsforge</commenter><contents>

    
      
          From LudwigBr...@gmail.com on May 14, 2013 19:35:34

Support for standard Android Fragments has been included in the rewrite branch, with an example for use in the Samples app. 

There will not be any changes or fixes for this issue in the 0.3 branch.

Status: Fixed  
      
    

  </contents></item><item><commenter/><contents/></item></comments><createtime>Nov 6, 2014, 5:41 PM GMT+8</createtime><closetime>Nov 6, 2014, 5:41 PM GMT+8</closetime></item></BR></extraction>