<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><extraction><clueid>118831028</clueid><fullpath><![CDATA[https://github.com/mapsforge/mapsforge/issues/205]]></fullpath><realpath><![CDATA[https://github.com/mapsforge/mapsforge/issues/205]]></realpath><theme>mapsforgex_item</theme><middle>default</middle><createdate>2015-8-23 17:51:59</createdate><baseURI><bucketBaseURI><bucketName>BR</bucketName><uri><![CDATA[https://github.com/mapsforge/mapsforge/issues/205]]></uri></bucketBaseURI></baseURI>
<BR><item><id>#205</id><title>Limit of the map</title><description>

    
      
          From carlito...@gmail.com on November 10, 2011 02:39:20

Hi Mapsforge team!

I'm very to use this mapping tool in my project, is working properply, and is very simple to use it. But I've a question about the loaded maps. I'm working in an offline project, and I'm using obviously a map file to do it. I would like that the users can't navigate more far than the limits of this map. Is it possible? It will be so nice to me.

Thanks for all!
Carlos

Original issue: http://code.google.com/p/mapsforge/issues/detail?id=205
      
    

  </description><comments><item><commenter>mapsforge</commenter><contents>

    
      
          From elpablos...@gmail.com on December 22, 2011 03:07:50

Implement it please, it is a must ! Set maximum and minimum coordinates to the map movement. Now, if the user moves the map, he can go out of barcelona city, but i dont want that, because i only am displaying the Barcelona city area, and the
rest of the world is WHITE.
      
    

  </contents></item><item><commenter>mapsforge</commenter><contents>

    
      
          From thilo.mu...@gmail.com on January 16, 2013 13:52:02

The whole mapsforge-map library is currently being rewritten from scratch. There is a Git branch called "rewrite" for that. One of the main ideas of the new implementation was to have only a single place in the code where the map position is stored and also chanced - the MapViewPosition class. This makes it easy to limit the zoom level range and also the navigable map position. You can set a bounding box as the map limit which will cannot be left.

I will keep this issue in state "Started" until we have released version 0.4.0 (which will probably take some more weeks).

Status: Started
  Owner: thilo.mu...@gmail.com  
      
    

  </contents></item><item><commenter>mapsforge</commenter><contents/></item></comments><createtime>Nov 6, 2014, 5:44 PM GMT+8</createtime><closetime>Nov 6, 2014, 5:44 PM GMT+8</closetime></item></BR></extraction>