<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><extraction><clueid>118829581</clueid><fullpath><![CDATA[https://github.com/mapsforge/mapsforge/issues/375]]></fullpath><realpath><![CDATA[https://github.com/mapsforge/mapsforge/issues/375]]></realpath><theme>mapsforgex_item</theme><middle>default</middle><createdate>2015-8-23 17:47:15</createdate><baseURI><bucketBaseURI><bucketName>BR</bucketName><uri><![CDATA[https://github.com/mapsforge/mapsforge/issues/375]]></uri></bucketBaseURI></baseURI>
<BR><item><id>#375</id><title>Support resolution-dependent images in render-themes</title><description>

    
      
          From LudwigBr...@gmail.com on November 21, 2012 13:22:19

The size of the icons provided in the AMV is too small for high dpi screens, they become pretty much unreadable.

Selecting an appropriate icon size for a display needs a new approach, best integrated with the standard Android way of selecting the right drawables from resources. 

I am currently not familiar how this could be achieved within the current rendertheme context, but I am willing to look into it. Does anyone have suggestions on how to do this?

However, the first step would be to produce higher res icons.

Is my impression right that the icons come from the OSM osmarender theme? http://svn.openstreetmap.org/applications/rendering/osmarender/stylesheets/symbols/

Original issue: http://code.google.com/p/mapsforge/issues/detail?id=375
      
    

  </description><comments><item><commenter>mapsforge</commenter><contents>

    
      
          From devemu...@gmail.com on November 25, 2012 08:21:30

"As the render-theme is supposed to be an Android-independent maven artifact, we might need to come up with some sort of interface for resource-providers which serves as an Adapter to the Android resource mechanism."

I think that osmdroid project has implemented such a mechanism, you can have a look at its classes of the 'library': https://code.google.com/p/osmdroid/source/browse/trunk/osmdroid-android/src/main/java/org/osmdroid/ResourceProxy.java https://code.google.com/p/osmdroid/source/browse/trunk/osmdroid-android/src/main/java/org/osmdroid/DefaultResourceProxyImpl.java And the extended class of an 'application' using them: https://code.google.com/p/osmdroid/source/browse/trunk/OpenStreetMapViewer/src/org/osmdroid/ResourceProxyImpl.java
      
    

  </contents></item><item><commenter>mapsforge</commenter><contents>

    
      
          From devemu...@gmail.com on April 16, 2013 06:20:18

Besides images, it would be nice for the labels to scale automatically depending on the screen dpi (regardless that there is the setTextScale method to do it manual).
      
    

  </contents></item><item><commenter/><contents/></item></comments><createtime>Nov 6, 2014, 5:58 PM GMT+8</createtime><closetime>Nov 6, 2014, 5:58 PM GMT+8</closetime></item></BR></extraction>