<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><extraction><clueid>118634002</clueid><fullpath><![CDATA[https://github.com/mapsforge/mapsforge/pull/599]]></fullpath><realpath><![CDATA[https://github.com/mapsforge/mapsforge/pull/599]]></realpath><theme>issue_599</theme><middle>default</middle><createdate>2015-8-22 22:37:53</createdate><baseURI><bucketBaseURI><bucketName>BR</bucketName><uri><![CDATA[https://github.com/mapsforge/mapsforge/pull/599]]></uri></bucketBaseURI></baseURI>
<BR><item><id>#599</id><title>AssetsRenderTheme shouldn't ignore relativePathPrefix</title><comments>
    

  
    
    

  




  

    
      lincomatic
    

    commented

    
      on Apr 10
    
  



  

    
      
          AssetsRenderTheme was ignoring relativePathPrefix, so symbol &amp; pattern folders had to be in root of assets.
      
    

  


  
  

  
    
      



  
      
  

    
      
    

    
      lincomatic
    

  
      AssetsRenderTheme shouldn't ignore relativePathPrefix


  

  
        
          

        


      cb30899
  


    
  


  
    
    

  


    Collaborator


  

    
      devemux86
    

    commented

    
      on Apr 10
    
  



  

    
      
          Thanks for the PR.

Actually the relativePathPrefix was primarily introduced for the case we use a render theme in assets that retrieve its resources from a jar (like mapsforge jar).
So the relativePathPrefix was the relative path inside the jar itself.

But I understand that we may have a similar case with assets paths too.

Nevertheless the relativePathPrefix is about the resources only.
The theme path can be fully described with the fileName parameter.
So I don't think we need the change in AssetsRenderTheme class.
      
    

  


  
  
    
    

  


    Collaborator


  

    
      devemux86
    

    commented

    
      on Apr 10
    
  



  

    
      
          A general note, please try following our code and style conventions (e.g. indentation).
      
    

  


  
  
  

  
      

  




  

    
      lincomatic
    

    commented on cb30899

    
      on Apr 10
    
  



  

    
      
          Sorry about the indentation. I use Emacs, which mixes spaces and tabs, and the indentation looked the same as yours in my git client. I will be careful to recheck it another way next time.

I would agree with that an easy workaround is to simply add the relative path prefixes to the assets: tags in the theme file. However, this makes the theme formats inconsistent between using file: and assets:. I noticed this when I was tweaking a theme using the SwingMapViewer, which am using with an Android app. Rather than just swapping "file:" and "assets:," I have to swap "file:" for "assets:relativepath/."

Also, it is confusing that  the AssetsRenderTheme constructor accepts a relativePathPrefix parameter, but essential ignores it.  Furthermore, the relativePathPrefix is handled consistently between "jar:" and "file:," so shouldn't it behave the same way with "assets:?"
      
    

  


  


  

  
    
      



  
      
  

    
      
    

    
      lincomatic
    

  
      fix indentation


  

  

        


      8e33ab5
  


    
  


  
    
    

  


    Collaborator


  

    
      devemux86
    

    commented

    
      on Apr 10
    
  



  

    
      
          We can make rendertheme-v4 external by replacing the assets: with file: prefix.
You just need to have in the same dir the render theme xml and the patterns / symbols folders, a common way of packaging render themes.

The relativePathPrefix is not ignored, as said it's handled when we use an assets render theme that declares resources from a jar.

About your PR, can you repost it with the AndroidGraphicFactory changes?
      
    

  


  
  

  
    
      



  
      
  

    
      
    

    
      lincomatic
    

  
      correct botched indentation fix commit


  

  

        


      bd1fff9
  


    
  


  
    
    

  




  

    
      lincomatic
    

    commented

    
      on Apr 11
    
  



  

    
      
          Actually, you just described the exact reason for my PR. Without my PR, when I use rendertheme-v4 as file: or jar: theme, it looks for the patterns/symbols folders as subfolder of relativePathPrefix, so I can package the whole theme in its own folder. But when used as assets:, it ignores relativePathPrefix, so the symbols/patterns are always relative to the root of assets.

Sorry, I am not very good with git. I don't know why the commit deleted my change to AndroidGraphicFactory, rather than fixing the indent. Will resubmit now.
      
    

  


  
  
    
    

  


    Collaborator


  

    
      devemux86
    

    commented

    
      on Apr 11
    
  



  

    
      
          Yes the relativePathPrefix is needed for assets too, the AndroidGraphicFactory changes are useful.

About GitHub, it's recommended for every PR to create a (dev) topic branch in your repository.
That allows you to build new features or test out ideas without putting your main branch at risk.
Of course you need to rebase it, each time dev changes.
(e.g. I have updated dev from your last fork)

You can read more in GitHub Help.
      
    

  


  
  
    
    

  




  

    
      lincomatic
    

    commented

    
      on Apr 11
    
  



  

    
      
          That is great advice. Thank you for the tip.
      
    

  


  
  
    
    

  


    Collaborator


  

    
      devemux86
    

    commented

    
      on Apr 11
    
  



  

    
      
          @lincomatic your latest code seems ok, but we don't need the changes for AssetsRenderTheme.
It refers to render theme xml path, which is described fine with the fileName parameter.

We only need the changes in AndroidGraphicFactory for the resources themselves.
      
    

  


  
  
    
    

  




  

    
      lincomatic
    

    commented

    
      on Apr 17
    
  



  

    
      
          Sorry for taking so long to reply.. I didn't see your latest comment until now.
Actually, we also need the change in AssetsRenderTheme, because the user instantiates the rendertheme by calling the constructor of AssetsRenderTheme(). If we only use the changes in AndroidGraphicFactory, there's no way to pass the relativePathPrefix down to AndroidGraphicFactory, so the change is useless.
      
    

  


  
  

  
      
          
          
          devemux86
          commented on the diff
          on Apr 17

      
    
      


  
    
        View full changes
    
    
      ...sforge/map/android/rendertheme/AssetsRenderTheme.java
    
  
  
    
            
    
      
        
      
    
    @@ -43,7 +43,7 @@ public AssetsRenderTheme(Context context, String relativePathPrefix, String file
  

    


    

    

  

     	public AssetsRenderTheme(Context context, String relativePathPrefix, String fileName, XmlRenderThemeMenuCallback menuCallback) throws IOException {

  


    


    

    

  

     		this.assetName = fileName;

  


    


    

    

  

     		this.relativePathPrefix = relativePathPrefix;

  



    
  



  

  


  
      

  
    


    Collaborator


  

    
      devemux86
    

    added a note

    
      on Apr 17
    
  



  

    
      
          The relativePathPrefix is passed down here.
      
    

  



  

  
  
    Add a line note

  

  
      
	Sign up for free
	to join this conversation on GitHub.
	Already have an account?
	Sign in to comment


  








    
  


  

  
      
          
          
          devemux86
          commented on the diff
          on Apr 17

      
    
      


  
    
        View full changes
    
    
      ...sforge/map/android/rendertheme/AssetsRenderTheme.java
    
  
  
    
            
    
      
        
      
    
    @@ -43,7 +43,7 @@ public AssetsRenderTheme(Context context, String relativePathPrefix, String file
  

    


    

    

  

     	public AssetsRenderTheme(Context context, String relativePathPrefix, String fileName, XmlRenderThemeMenuCallback menuCallback) throws IOException {

  


    


    

    

  

     		this.assetName = fileName;

  


    


    

    

  

     		this.relativePathPrefix = relativePathPrefix;

  


    


    

    

  

    -		this.inputStream = context.getAssets().open(this.assetName);

  


    


    

    

  

    +		this.inputStream = context.getAssets().open((this.relativePathPrefix == null) ? "" : this.relativePathPrefix + this.assetName);

  



    
  



  

  


  
      

  
    


    Collaborator


  

    
      devemux86
    

    added a note

    
      on Apr 17
    
  



  

    
      
          Here we parse the render theme xml file, i.e. fileName parameter which becomes assetName variable.

The xml file path can be totally described by this, so we don't need any mix with the relativePathPrefix which is for the resources paths in the xml itself.
      
    

  



  

  
  
    Add a line note

  

  
      
	Sign up for free
	to join this conversation on GitHub.
	Already have an account?
	Sign in to comment


  








    
  


  
    
    

  


    Collaborator


  

    
      devemux86
    

    commented

    
      on May 16
    
  



  

    
      
          Any news on this?
      
    

  


  
  
    
    

  




  

    
      lincomatic
    

    commented

    
      on May 19
    
  



  

    
      
          Excluding this change:


      this.inputStream = context.getAssets().open(this.assetName);
      this.inputStream = context.getAssets().open((this.relativePathPrefix == null) ? "" : this.relativePathPrefix + this.assetName);


forces the theme XML file to be stored in the root of the assets, unless we instantiate AssetsRenderTheme with fileName=relativePathPrefix+fileName. I have a rendertheme that's stored like this:
osma/
osma/mysomatheme.xml
osma/patterns
osma/symbols

Without my change, we need to use
AssetsRenderTheme(context,"osma","osma/mysosmatheme.xml"....
This is redundant, and unexpected, since the parameter is called "fileName," not filePath. 
If you feel strongly about it, I don't mind, It might be easier to just close this PR and make the changes the way you like them, since my PR ugly, with 3 commits.
      
    

  


  
  
    
    

  


    Collaborator


  

    
      devemux86
    

    commented

    
      on May 19
    
  



  

    
      
          Ok now I understand better what you mean.
I don't oppose to the changes, but can you squash the commits into one?

I posted some instructions here:
https://groups.google.com/d/msg/mapsforge-dev/AK3yjjd8E6s/a6Ct5V7b-i8J
      
    

  


  
  
      
    
      

      
      lincomatic

      referenced
      this pull request
      
        on May 20
      
    

      
          
        Merged
      



    
      
        AssetsRenderTheme shouldn't ignore relativePathPrefix
        #612
    
    
  


  
    
    

  




  

    
      lincomatic
    

    commented

    
      on May 20
    
  



  

    
      
          I tried squashing but every time I synced it, the squash would get undone, because I had already pushed it to the remote. Hope you don't mind.. I just created a new PR instead. 
#612
      
    

  


  
  
    
    

  


    Collaborator


  

    
      devemux86
    

    commented

    
      on May 20
    
  



  

    
      
          @lincomatic it's ok, Git is very powerful but it can get equally hard to manage too.
      
    

  


  
  


      


  
    

      
      
      devemux86
      closed this   on May 20
    
  

  




      


  
    

      
      
      lincomatic
      deleted the  lincomatic:dev branch on May 20
    
  





      


  
    

      
      
      devemux86
      added the bug label on Jul 21
    
  





      


  
    

      
      
      devemux86
      added this to the 0.5.2 milestone on Jul 21
    
  









    



  </comments></item></BR></extraction>