<extraction><id>#28</id><title>[CLOSED] Other device is republishing my events</title><description> Issue by jpmens from Saturday Jan 25, 2014 at 13:43 GMT
Originally opened as binarybucks/mqttitude#303I've been noticing this for a few days, and I'm trying to track it down. (both devices: iOS with 5.5 on them)It seems to me as though my ENTER/LEAVE events are being republished by my wife's device. I have verified that her phone does NOT have this waypoint set up. Even so, my (5s) events are sort-of republished as hers (4s).by "sort-of" I mean the event and desc are being copied in. Her tst and location are correct for her device.</description><comments>Comment by binarybucks from Saturday Jan 25, 2014 at 13:45 GMTI'll check if it's my brokerMit freundlichen Gr  en / With kind regards
Alexander Rust
--Sent from mobile
Am 25.01.2014 14:43 schrieb "JP Mens" notifications@github.com:I've been noticing this for a few days, and I'm trying to track it down.
(both devices: iOS with 5.5 on them)It seems to me as though my ENTER/LEAVE events are being republished by my
wife's device. I have verified that her phone does NOT have this waypoint
set up. Even so, my (5s) events are sort-of republished as hers (4s).by "sort-of" I mean the event and desc are being copied in. Her tst and
location are correct for her device.00376 2014-01-25 10:34:41 mqttitude/jpm/5s {"acc": "65", "_type": "location", "lon": "y.532743", "batt": "95", "lat": "x.018992", "tst": "1390642481", "event": "leave", "desc": "Ratsgymnasium"}
00377 2013-12-19 12:59:41 mqttitude/jpm/5s {"acc": "10", "rad": "150", "lon": "y.528701", "_type": "waypoint", "batt": "95", "lat": "x.019256", "tst": "1387454381", "desc": "Ratsgymnasium"}
00378 2014-01-25 10:36:11 mqttitude/jpm/5s {"acc": "65", "_type": "location", "lon": "y.532747", "batt": "95", "lat": "x.019103", "tst": "1390642571"}00379 2014-01-25 10:36:54 mqttitude/yak/4s {"acc": "65", "_type": "location", "lon": "y.532368", "batt": "35", "lat": "x.019925", "tst": "1390642614", "event": "leave", "desc": "Ratsgymnasium"} 
Reply to this email directly or view it on GitHubbinarybucks/mqttitude#303
. Comment by jpmens from Saturday Jan 25, 2014 at 13:47 GMTIt isn't. This happened before you set up your bridge.  Comment by jpmens from Saturday Jan 25, 2014 at 13:48 GMT@ckrey Here's another example. Interestingly, the timestamps are the wrong way around this time.And you can believe me: she wouldn't have entered a waypoint called $HoMe ;-) Comment by jpmens from Saturday Jan 25, 2014 at 13:59 GMT@ckrey Another hint: this occurred yesterday morning: a friend who uses my broker approached the company we're both working at, and I recognized a PUB of his containing my waypoint description.It's as though the iPhone stores the waypoints/geo-fences but doesn't differentiate (when recognizing in/out of a fence) whom the waypoint actually belongs to, and thus just publishes it as its own.Do I get a prize? :-) Comment by ckrey from Saturday Jan 25, 2014 at 14:28 GMT@jpmens I found the bug two days ago already. It's fixed. And I think this is a trigger to upgrade to 5.6 Comment by ckrey from Saturday Jan 25, 2014 at 14:30 GMTClosed with binarybucks/mqttitude@3039eec</comments></extraction>