<extraction><id>#64</id><title>Freeze map size</title><description> I'm experimenting with using OwnTracks for Android on a tablet to display multiple moving 'people'. I click on a friend and see him on the map. I then pinch the map to get a better overview.As soon as a person moves, the map zooms in to that person.Could we have a 'freeze map size' kind of thing somewhere? This would enable using OwnTracks on a tablet to view several people moving at once.In addition, the 'freeze map size' thing would also ideally use the screen real-estate at the bottom of the screen where the geocoder displays.</description><comments>thing would also ideally use the screen real-estate at the bottom of the screen where the geocoder displays 
The problem is that there is no real-estate left on most mobile devicesWould it be sufficient to zoom in on the contact once you select it form the list and just center the map without zooming in on location updates of that contact? If you deselect the contact by tapping on the map it already freezes the map. So you would get a tracking mode with the current zoom level when you select the contact and a frozen map when you deselect a contact.  The use-case is a standing tablet where one can see a bunch of people moving without the map itself moving. If I understand you correctly, you want the map to 'follow' a single person? That's not what I'm after. Just tap the map then, it will stop following that contact ^^Your problem is that the map centers when you tap the person, right?
I think it's kind of neat to follow a person around but I've no idea where to add UI elements to make the tracking optional. For now I suggest that I make the behavior the same as in the iOS app and disable the follow mode on location updates: 
select contact from the list: show contact details, center and zoom in on contact
select contact from map: show contact details, no centering and no zooming Good The new behavior should fit your needs. I added a context menu entry to follow/unfollow a contact. Follow mode enabled centers (not zooms) the contact on location updates. 
Follow mode disables just updates the information of the selected contact
The show button zooms in and centers the contact once  How do I associate a name/face from address book to a topic? Details context menu doesn't seem to allow me to set anything. long-hold the three dots next to the name field. A context menu to "link" the contact should appear. 
That's one of those rough edges ;) I thought I'd held long enough, sorry. Yeah, works, thanks.</comments></extraction>