<extraction><id>#70</id><title>Add AltBeacon support</title><description> This would enable far more granular location reporting. I plan to hack this into the OwnTracks Android client for my own use, but if there's interest, I'll make an effort to contribute it back to the community.Android AltBeacon library: AltBeacon/android-beacon-library (Apache v2 license)
AltBeacon spec
AltBeacon homepageSome misc AltBeacon details: AltBeacons are similar to iBeacons; they use Bluetooth Low Energy devices to broadcast a packet with a specific format. They can be purchased as USB dongles, battery powered tags, or emulated on linux systems with cheap bluetooth dongles. (I'm currently running an AltBeacon on of my Raspberry Pi's and a $10 BLE dongle.)Use case: I'm working towards using Owntracks and Node-Red to control a home automation system. I can turn off various equipment when I leave my house - PC monitors, audio amplifiers, lights, etc. AltBeacon support would give far more granular location control - rather than turning off my devices when I'm a mile away from home, I'll be able to turn them off when I'm X meters away from my room.My current intention is to copy the data format being used on iOS for iBeacon reporting. It looks like all of the fields used when reporting iBeacons have AltBeacon counterparts.Any feedback would be appreciated, thanks!</description><comments>I'm not familiar with these, but it sounds sensible, particularly since you want to copy the iOS data formats, so yes, do please go ahead, and we'll gladly accept code. :-) @GeorgeHahn With the new code and disabled bluetooth I'm continuously getting the following log error message, could you look into this?Also, if I disable bluetooth after scanning starts, it outputs Bluetooth is disabled.  Cannot scan for beacons. at the rate of scanning continuously. If we add an option to start/stop it while the app is running it should also stop trying  Can do. If I abort scanning, do you know if there's a way I can get notified if the user turns bluetooth back on? Got it. I was trying to set background mode even when ranging was disabled. @GeorgeHahn could you look at #126 ? 
There seems to be an issue for handling preferences in the beacon service. </comments></extraction>